Pammi Kumari

ReactJs developer, Frontend developer

pammisao1234@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/pammi-kumari-099978179/ | github.com/PammiKumari1234

Profile

As a Frontend Developer with 3 years of experience. I have a strong foundation in frontend development, problem solving and debugging skills, specialized in React, JavaScript and typeScript.

Skills and Competencies

ReactJs | JavaScript | TypeScript | Redux | HTML | CSS | API Integration | Git and Version Control | Agile Development Methodologies | Webpack/Babel and Build Tools

Professional Experience

Systems Engineer, TCS Jan 2023 – present | Bangalore, India Key Responsibilities:

- Developed and implemented responsive user interface using React, ensuring a seamless and engaging user experience and Redux for managing application state.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers and backend developers, to translate design specification into functional code.
- Integrated RESTful APIs to fetch and update data, optimizing application performance and responsiveness.
- Utilized Webpack and Babel for bundling and transpiling JavaScript code.

Senior Software Engineer, Capgemini Jan 2021 – Jan 2023 | Kolkata, India

Key Responsibilities:

- Worked with web development technologies such as React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML. My role involved implementing Bootstrap plugins to create dynamic components like carousels, accordions, and modal windows.
- I excelled in identifying and developing highlyresponsive user components, ensuring an enhanced and engaging user experience.

Training and Internships

Engineering Intern, JBS Capacitors Pvt Ltd

Apr 2020 – Dec 2020 | Bhubaneswar, India

Worked on a data annotation project using python.

Worked on a web development project using HTML, CSS.

Intern, Syllogistek Systems Private Ltd
Jun 2019 – Jun 2019 | Bhubaneswar, India
Worked on a web development project using HTML, CSS,
JavaScript, JSON, PHP.

Projects

Food Ordering Application, is a food ordering webpage created using React, HTML, CSS. The restaurant menu is coming from live API of swiggy.com.

Github- https://github.com/PammiKumari1234/namastereact

Live link- https://namaste-react-phi-one.vercel.app/

My Portfolio, showcases as a comprehensive showcase of my skills, projects, work experience, education. Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js has user friendly navigation and responsive layout. In the project section, it has several other project which I had created.

Github- https://github.com/PammiKumari1234/My-Portfolio

Live link- https://pammikumari1234.github.io/My-Portfolio/

Achievements

AZ 900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals, 2022

Education

Masters of Computer Application, Silicon Institute of Technology

July 2018 – April 2020 | Bhubaneswar, India

CGPA- 8.2

Languages

- English
- Hindi